# **EIKE STEFFEN** KOHLMEYER

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER





**1** +49 151 67204928



ekohlmeyer21@gmail.com



Trausnitzstr. 8, 81671, Munich



https://github.com/EikeKohl



https://shorturl.at/aJK49

## PROFILE

Passionate team player experienced in applied Machine Learning, particularly NLP. My experience spans the entire MLOps lifecycle, and I am experienced in the application of Large Language Models. My high intrinsic motivation, skillset, and solution-oriented work style make me an excellent fit for your position.

# SKILLS

Python - 4 years

**SQL** - 4 years

scikit-learn - 4 years

numpy / pandas - 4 years

**Tensorflow** - 3 years

Pytorch - 2 years

Git - 2 years

Docker - 2 years

Linux - 2 years

MS Azure - 2 year

AWS - 1.5 years

deepspeed - 1 year

**DBT** - 1 year

# EXPERIENCE

#### MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

SCAILEX GmbH - Munich, Germany 12/2021 - 08/2023

I am responsible for the complete MLOps lifecycle including training. In this position, I was able to develop my skillset as a machine learning practitioner as well as a software engineer. Please refer to the "Projects" section for relevant projects and technologies used.

#### **DATA SCIENTIST**

Atruvia AG - Munich, Germany

12/2020 - 11/2021

As a Data Scientist at an IT Service Provider for banks. I developed DL / ML applications in a banking context. Please refer to the "Projects" section for relevant projects and technologies used.

# EDUCATION

## **BUSINESS ANALYTICS | M.SC.**

Hochschule Düsseldorf

2019 - 2020

FINANCE, ACCOUNTING, **CONTROLLING AND** TAXES | B.SC.

Fachhochschule Dortmund

2014 - 2018

## **WORKING STUDENT - ASSET, LIABILITY** AND CAPITAL MANAGEMENT

HSBC - Düsseldorf, Germany

06/2019 - 08/2020

#### **AUDITOR BANKS & ASSET MANAGEMENT**

KPMG AG - Zurich. Switzerland

10/2018 - 12/2018

## TRAINEE AUDIT ASSET MANAGEMENT

KPMG Société coopérative - Luxembourg, Luxembourg 02/2018 - 08/2018

## LANGUAGES

German - native

English - fluent

## CERTIFICATES

MLOps Engineering for Production (Coursera)

Spezialization NLP (Coursera)

**Deep Learning Specialization** (Coursera)

Tensorflow Developer (Google)

Tensorflow Advanced Techniques (Coursera)

**Azure Data Scientist Associate** (Microsoft)

## INTERESTS







Guitar Calisthenics Programming

# **PROJECTS**

### AI LAWYER (WIP)

AWS - Huggingface - Pytorch - DeepSpeed - OpenAl Research and prototyping for an instruction-based, German LLM using RLHF, capable of:

- 1. Understanding legal cases,
- 2. Identifying applicable legal contexts,
- 3. Autonomously asking questions to obtain information relevant to the claim.

## INFORMATION RETRIEVAL (LLM)

LangChain - OpenAI - Huggingface - AWS - Streamlit

I have developed multiple Information Retrieval pipelines that utilize a vectorized knowledge database to enhance LLM prompts (e.g. ChatGPT) with contextual information, resulting in personalized and fact-based chatbot interactions. The services have been deployed on AWS, utilizing terraform Infrastructure as Code to ensure that authentication, load balancing, and other essential features are implemented effectively. Public reference:

https://github.com/EikeKohl/paperqa-web-app

#### INFORMATION EXTRACTION (NER & OCR)

Sagemaker - Huggingface - Pytorch - MLflow - AWS Lambda

Training, evaluation, deployment, and monitoring of information extraction models. In the context of the legal domain, this involves Named Entity Recognition (NER) of pertinent details from client, court, and insurance correspondence. To achieve this, I utilized transformers-based architectures and a BiLSTM-CRF ensemble model approach. Additionally, my team and I developed an Optical Character Recognition model to extract information from images sent by customers, employing a YOLOv5 + TrOCR model ensemble. Experiments for model training were conducted on Sagemaker and tracked in MLflow.

#### **DOCUMENT CLASSIFICATION**

Sagemaker - Huggingface - Pytorch - MLflow - AWS Lambda

As a Machine Learning Engineer, I've trained, evaluated, and deployed document classification models for SCAILEX and its SaaS platform handling 500,000+ annual documents from various sources. Using SWEM and transformers-based approaches, we achieved a 60% automation rate with 95% accuracy. Model training experiments were conducted on Sagemaker and tracked in MLflow for efficient development.

#### **OTHER**

AWS - DBT - SQL - CI/CD - Package Registry - Huggingface - Pytorch - pydantic - CLI - Jupyter - Tensorflow - HDFS - Docker

- Usage of Dynamic Time Warping to reconstruct reference time series based on real-life time series data
- Implementation of Interpretable ML approaches
- Automatic Speech Recognition in banking context
- Bosch **Hand Pose Detection** Hackathon
- Developed internal "Dr.Prepper" data preparation pipeline tool for NLP
- Implemented ML data mart on Amazon Redshift using DBT